ANISHA HIRANI

anisha.hirani11@gmail.com Tel: 07562314978 GitHub CV

PERSONAL PROFILE:

A recent graduate from Makers Academy pursuing a software development career with a past experience of tutoring in the education sector. I was inspired by seeing how vital technology was within the current education system. This pushed me further to take up code and stem a career out of it.

I'm currently heavily involved with a non-profit organisation called HSS UK and have been for the past 14 years which instils the ethos of hard work, good morals, selfless working and aligns with my passion for tech for good. I pride myself in managing my time, having managed my studies, personal life and professional development successfully up until this point.

PROJECTS:

ReelPlaces	Built a web-app in a team so users see filming locations in their chosen location, with a map.	Tech Stack: React Native, Jest, MongoDB, Express, Node.
Acebook	Built a web-app in a team, similar to Facebook - make posts,comment, like etc.	Tech Stack: MERN Stack, Jest, Cypress, Mongoose, Handlebars.
<u>MakersBnB</u>	A web-app similar to AirBnB that allows you to rent a space, make bookings etc.	Tech Stack: Ruby, PostgreSQL, Sinatra, RSpec.
Portfolio Site	A solo project to showcase the projects that I have worked on.	Tech Stack: Javascript, HTML, Tailwind CSS, Next.js Vercel

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE:

Makers Academy

(Oct 2022 - Feb 2023)

- A 16-week intensive software development bootcamp focussed on key languages like; Ruby, Javascript, SQL, HTML & CSS, Sinatra and more that helped testing and improved my technical skills.
- Daily pair programmed with multiple individuals, as well as focussed on self learning and improvement.
- Concentrated on Object-Oriented Programming and Test Driven Development
- Balanced time between being patient with producing code when working alongside my peers.
- I debugged and refactored my code as well as pre-written code for better learning and understanding.
- Used my curiosity and initiative with my little knowledge of Github as it was key to managing control.
- I worked on lots of team projects that involved API's, but I worked on features that involved Google Maps and IMDb API's.
- I am currently going over some JavaScript content using Codecademy to build new and fresh projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Hindu Swayamsevak Sangh (HSS UK)

(Jan 2009 - Present)

Volunteer

Organisation to bring Hindus around the world together through the use of the religion, culture, spiritual and physical development.

- Organise and control weekly activities to promote spiritual development, service to humanity and unity through Hindu ideology.
- Responsible for supporting all ages and developing them through regular weekly activities consisting of games, yoga, health & fitness, educational and cultural from ages 5 to 70 + years.
- Attention to detail required when leading monthly meetings, working under pressure to meet deadlines and obtaining feedback to keep the sessions running effectively.
- Communication and self organisation was vital when ensuring everybody was receiving the same development opportunities.
- Worked in a team to successfully manage and oversee a yoga session with the local temple in the public community for International Yoga Day.
- Taking charge and collaborating frequently with new people to orchestrate charitable events and develop our selfless work.

Explore Learning (Feb 2021 - Dec 2022)

Tutor

- Maths and English Tutor to over 70 students.
- Responsible for delivering high quality lessons on a regular basis.
- Adapting to children's different learning abilities, as well as being able to empathise with them.
- Communicating with parents to provide relevant child feedback and immediately acting upon it.
- Having a great amount of patience when explaining tough concepts to the class.
- Taking out extra time to plan lessons based on the child's ability.

EDUCATION:

Plumstead Manor Sixth Form

(Sept 2020 - Jul 2022)

A-Levels in Mathematics, Economics and Financial Studies

Plumstead Manor School

(Sept 2015 - Jul 2020)

12 GCSEs including Gujarati.

INTERESTS:

- Travelling
- Music playing piano & singing
- Various sports & going to the gym
- Volunteering